boots.jobs 2019-07-31

# Privacy Statement - Boots Jobs - Career Opportunities with Boots

**1.     Our promise to you**  
Boots is committed to protecting your privacy.   We will always keep your personal information safe and will never sell it to third parties.  We’ll be clear and open with you about why we collect your personal information and how we use it. Where you have choices, we’ll explain them to you and respect your wishes.

**2.     Who’s in control of your information?**  
Throughout this Privacy Policy, ‘we’ or ‘Boots’ means Walgreens Boots Alliance Services Limited which, for the purposes of the Data Protection legislation, is a ‘Data Controller’. You can also find lots of useful information about Data Protection, what it means to you as an individual and how it applies to companies like Boots on the Information Commissioner’s website at <http://ico.org.uk/> Office of Data Protection Commissioner for the Republic of Ireland [https://dataprotection.ie](https://dataprotection.ie/)

**3.     Using information about you**

We use the personal information you provide to set up your Boots Jobs account to notify you of suitable vacancies if you have asked us to do so, and process any applications you make.  If you apply for a job at Boots UK we may use your information to carry out checks with external sources such as the DBS (Disclosure and Barring Service) and fraud prevention agencies to verify your identity and assess your suitability for certain roles (e.g. Pharmacist, PDC Drivers and Dispensers).  For applications for a job at Boots Ireland we will use the National Vetting Bureau to verify your identity and assess your suitability for certain roles (e.g. Pharmacist).

If you apply for a job with Boots, some of the information we ask you to provide may be sensitive in nature, such as information about your health. We will only ask for sensitive information where we have a specific need for it and we will always tell you why we need it. We will not use your data in any other way or share it with unauthorised third parties.

Examples include necessary adjustments for interviews and assessments, diversity and inclusions information including equal opportunities.

If your job application is successful, the information you give during the application process will form part of your employee record and will be used to administer your employment and manage your career at Boots.

If your application is unsuccessful we will retain your information collected during the application process for 12 months, including interview notes and assessment results.  If your application is unsuccessful you will also be unable to apply for jobs via your Boots Jobs account for 12months.

If you’ve give us permission to do so, we may contact you during this time with details of other vacancies that we believe are suited to you and that you may be interested in.

We may also contact you for feedback on our recruitment processes in order to enable us to make continuous improvements to our process.

We use profiling as part of our recruitment process.  This helps us provide a fair and consistent recruitment process.  You can find information about why we use profiling, including the logic involved, the mathematic and statistical procedures we use below. Once you’ve completed any necessary assessments we always use human intervention to ensure the right decisions are made about the next steps in your recruitment journey.

You can ask us to close your account at any time by contacting Colleague Administration Support Services at [colleagueaccessrequest@boots.co.uk](mailto:colleagueaccessrequest@boots.co.uk)

We will keep your personal information such as your online assessment results for a limited time after the account is closed to enable us to fulfil our legal and regulatory obligations, carry out internal validation and process any queries.  If your Boots Jobs account is inactive for 12 months we will close it.

**4.     Information We Collect Online: Cookies**  
A ‘cookie’ is a file in your web browser that enables us to recognise your computer when you visit the Boots Jobs website and make using the site quicker and easier.  Cookies are also essential to the functioning of certain parts of the site and we use them to collect information about how the site is used.  The Boots Jobs website uses Cookies in the following ways:

  * **Making our website work:**  
These Cookies are essential so that you can move around the site and log in to your account.
  * **Enabling the features of the website:**  
These Cookies allow our website to remember choices you have made, such as your user name and help us provide you with a better, more personal experience.  They also help us show you job adverts for roles that you might like to apply for.
  * **Monitoring and improving the performance of the website:**  
These Cookies collect information about how visitors use the site, e.g. which pages they visit most often or how many visitors complete an application. We share this information with external companies that carry out analysis to help us improve our website, but the information is aggregated and does not identify individual people.

Some parts of our site need Cookies in order to function correctly.  By default, Cookies should be enabled on your computer or device, and although you can ‘disable’ them in your browser this will affect your experience of the website and you may experience technical issues with some of the site’s features.

If you’d still prefer to restrict, block or delete Cookies from this or any other website, it’s easy to do in your internet browser. Each browser is different, so you’ll need to go to the ‘help’ menu on your browser and look for how to change your ‘cookie preferences’.

For independent information about Cookies, visit [www.aboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)

**5.     Privacy, Cookies and shared computers**  
If you log in to the site from a shared computer, such as in an internet cafe or from a colleague’s computer at work, Cookies may cause your e-mail address or user name to display in the login field to anyone who uses the site on that computer after you.  You can avoid this by clearing the Cookies stored by the web browser.  The option to do this is normally in the ‘Tools’ dropdown menu at the top of the browser window.

**6.     Sharing your information outside the Walgreens Boots Alliance Group**

Boots may share your personal information with external companies that provide services on our behalf. Where we do this we ensure they give your information the same level of care and security as we do.

We use a number of agencies to help us recruit. The agencies will share candidate details with us where they believe the candidates are suitable for roles and have agreement from the candidate (we will make sure that agencies always share our privacy policy before sharing candidate’s details with us).

Some assessments that candidates will take mean that their data will be passed to our assessment providers. We pseudonymised data were we can, but where this isn’t possible we limit the information that we share to only that the minimum that is required.

We may share your Personal Information with third parties where required or permitted by law, if we believe we need to do so to protect our rights, or to comply with legal proceedings. In such cases we will always do so legally and with due regard to your privacy.

If ownership of all or part of our business changes or we undergo a reorganisation (including a merger or transfer between Walgreens Boots Alliance companies), we will transfer your personal information to the new owner or successor company so we can continue to provide our services.

**7.     Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
This Privacy Policy was updated in May 2018. We may review it from time to time so we recommend that you check back here occasionally.  If we make any changes that we think may significantly affect you, particularly if they could have an impact on your rights under Data Protection legislation, we will notify you.

**8.      Staying in control of your information**

We respect the fact that your personal information is  ** _your  _**information, and we’ll make it easy for you to update or change your personal details. Please help us to help you by letting us know if your contact details change or if you spot any errors in the information we hold about you.

If you would like a copy of the information Boots holds about you, if you would like to request that Boots delete your information, stop processing your information or have any queries about the way Boots handles your personal information, please contact our Colleague Administration Support Services at [colleagueacessrequest@boots.co.uk](mailto:colleagueacessrequest@boots.co.uk)

## Profiling as part of our recruitment process

At Boots UK & ROI we use profiling in the recruitment process for some roles, particularly when we receive a high volume of applications, as we feel it’s the fairest and most consistent way to determine your suitability to join us. It also helps you to find out as quickly as possible if your application is being considered further.

Some of our online assessments ask how you respond to challenges you are most likely to face in the role. Some also ask about your personality preferences in a work place setting. These scenarios and questions have been selected because they link to the behaviours and personality traits shown to be most effective for the role. If you respond in similar way to high performing Colleagues, it is likely that you too will be a great fit for the role.

Candidate information (such as eligibility to work in the UK/ROI, availability to work the required hours etc.) along with a minimum overall role match score on your assessment profile, will determine whether your application is progressed.  Of those who are progressed, candidates who most closely match the requirements for the role are prioritised for the next stage. We have experienced members of staff on hand throughout our recruitment process to perform checks to ensure all candidates are going through the same fair recruitment process, from reviewing role match scores, reviewing responses to questions, and during the interview process. A Hiring Manager will ultimately make a selection decision, based on your performance during a face-to-face assessment.

**Your right to complain to the ICO if resident in the UK or the DPC if resident in the Republic of Ireland**

Although we hope it never comes to this, you do have the right to complain to the ICO/DPC about any of the Boots data processing activates. You can contact the ICO office in the UK at [casework@ico.org.uk](mailto:casework@ico.org.uk). OR contact the DPC office in the ROI at [info@dataprotection.ie](mailto:info@dataprotection.ie)
